[music]
[Instructor] Cool. So we've got
some background music
playing in our game [happy game music]
for our nice happy forest,
and our nice happy character
jumping through the Scene.
So, one of the last things
that we're going to do
is we're going to add in some
"Sound Effects" for the Player.
Now Sound Effects are a bit
different than using Music Audio
because we actually need
to trigger those Sound Effects
in our code. So actually,
what we're going to do is,
first we're going to go
into our PlayerController Script,
and now in our PlayerController Script,
we're going to create
two new variables.
So the first one will be a public,
and in this case,
since we're actually using Audio clips,
we can actually just use
the "AudioClip".
So now we have an AudioClip class.
And we'll call this,
The "jumpSound."
And then we need a second
AudioClip for our "crashSound."
So now that we have
these public variables,
now if we go back into Unity,
you can see when we click
on the Player,
so there's the Jump Sound
which has no Audio Clip,
and the Crash Sound
which also has no Audio Clip.
So we're actually going to go
into the "SFX."
So there's a bunch of different
options for jumping and crashing.
So if we just make sure
that we go back to the Player,
and we'll just drag one of them.
I'll just do crash2 for our crash sound.
And then jump3 for our jump sound.
So now what you're going to do is,
in your PlayerController class,
you're going to create
two new variables yourself
for the AudioClips.
One AudioClip variable for the jump,
and one for the crash,
and make sure that they're public,
so that way we can assign it,
when we get into Unity.
And then in Unity, you're going to click
the Player,
and then just make sure that you go
into your Course Library, Sound,
SFX for Sound Effects.
Drag and drop one of the jumps
into the jump sound,
and one of the crashes
into the crash sound.
Now it's your turn.
[music]